<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="58"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Rugeley Power Station













                                                         Remediation Works





                                                                      Site Induction










                                           Safety Culture “Say what you see”]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Site Health, Safety & Environmental induction]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[General Information









                    •      This site health, safety and environmental induction will tell you about the project


                           and the arrangements that have been made to control the health, safety and

                           environmental risks during the works.



                    •      These Health, Safety, Environmental (HSE) and security rules stipulate the

                           minimum requirements for the safe completion of this project.




                    •      Health and safety is everyone’s responsibility. If you observe an unsafe

                           act/situation or receive an injury whilst at work, YOU MUST REPORT IT!




                    •      Question unsafe acts and be open to change when questioned without

                           confrontation.



                    •      Please present CSCS and/or CPCS cards and all other certification to the site


                           manager if you are operating plant, equipment and tools on site for the work you

                           are employed  to undertake. No cards = no work on site.



                    •      Please make sure you have understood this induction and the rules on this

                           project. If in doubt, ask. Never assume.




                    •      Please ensure you have signed onto the appropriate Risk Assessment/Method

                           statement (RAMS) before commencing work. If it is not detailed in the RAMS

                           then do not do it and consult your supervisor.




                    •      Do not wear PPE when using local shops.]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[General Information









                    John F Hunt Regeneration Ltd are certificated to:






                    •      ISO9001:2015 – Quality Management. This is the international standard that


                           specifies requirements for a quality management system (QMS). Organisations

                           use the standard to demonstrate the ability to consistently provide products and

                           services that meet customer and regulatory requirements;






                    •      ISO14001:2015 – Environmental Management System. The international

                           standard that specifies the requirements for an environmental management


                           system that an organisation can use to enhance its environmental performance;






                    •      ISO45001:2018 – Occupational Health and Safety Management System.

                           This is a new international standard that provides a framework for an

                           Organisation to manage risks and opportunities to help prevent work-related

                           injury and ill health to workers.






                    Employees and contractors have a responsibility to work in accordance with these

                    standards and strive for continual improvement.]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Project details








                  Client:                     Engie UK




                  JFH Project Manager:  Guy Thring



                  JFH Site Manager: Dean Holland




                  The works consist of the following;


                  •      Installation of site setup – Double stacked offices, canteen, toilet and drying room facility with generator.


                  •      Check of a boundary fence, completing repairs where required which is the existing perimeter site boundary fence.


                  •      The works on site are for:


                                          ➢ The Remediation of site soils for Chemical constituents and for asbestos


                                          ➢ The cut to fill earthworks across the site, validated by CBT testing.


                                          ➢ Removal and breaking out of the Old Boiler House and Turbine Hall basements & underground

                                          obstructions to 1.5m below formation level.


                                          ➢ Surface protection at enabling formation level.


                                          ➢ The removal of 2 sets of Modular buildings.


                                          ➢ Management of surface and ground water within the parameters of the discharge permit.


                                          ➢ Tree felling and De-vegetation works.


                                          ➢ Continuous soil sampling and water PH testing.


                                          ➢ Excavation and removal of Chromium contaminated soils.]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Project details




             •      Should any asbestos be encountered, this will be supervised by competent asbestos operatives, and should it be

                    classified at licensed material works stopped and correct measures implemented.


             •      In order to undertake any licensed asbestos works only CAT C trained operatives with a valid face fit test are
                    permitted into the licensed area when wearing all of the correct PPE and RPE.


             •      Any asbestos material found will be handpicked and double bagged and this will be put into sealed asbestos skips.



             •      The material will then be tested. Once results are received, the material will be classified, issued to the client for
                    agreement and then relocated on site and placed at depth.


             •      Should any gross asbestos be visually identified this will be photographed, agreed with the client, and only then

                    excavated and put straight into a lined skip. Once wrapped removed.

             •      Chemical constituents expected to be encountered are hydrocarbon contamination, and heavy metals associated

                    with pulverised fuel ash.]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Project details




             • Site Overview Plan.]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Key Personnel on Site















                       Project Manager:                                                                      Guy Thring






                       Site Manager:                                                                         Dean Holland







                       JFH Geotech & Environmental:                                                          Chris Oates


                                                                                                              Hannah Corran


                                                                                                              James Adley







                       Site Supervisors:                                                                     John Hawthorn


                                                                                                              Ross McGuire






                       Health, Safety & Environmental:                                                       Steve Blundell (Site)


                                                                                                              Keith Kelsey  (Head office)










                       Management can be found in the site office.]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Coronavirus (Covid-19)
















         Coronavirus is a virus that affects the respiratory system (lungs). Covid-19 is the


         Infection and can be spread between people within 2 metres of each other, possibly

         inhaled into the lungs via air born water droplets from a cough or a sneeze.

         Infection can be transferred by hand to face after touching an infected surface or

         object.




         Site management to use the CITB toolbox  on Coronavirus talk to communicate

         common controls.



         ✓ Wherever possible travel to site alone, using your own transport (for example,  a car


                 or bicycle). Avoid public transport.



         ✓ Always keep at least 2 metres away from other workers. Work to be planned to

                 prevent close working.


         ✓ Understand the risks of COVID-19


         ✓ Keep yourself and others safe

         ✓ Get tested and self-isolate if required]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Coronavirus (Covid-19)


















         Cleaning - Extra cleaning will be carried out on site, particularly in the following areas:





         ✓ Taps and washing facilities,





         ✓ Toilet flush and seats,






         ✓ Door handles and push plates,





         ✓ Handrails on staircases and corridors,





         ✓ Food preparation, eating surfaces and appliances,





         ✓ Telephone equipment, Keyboards, photocopiers  and other office equipment.





         ✓ Lift and hoist controls, machinery and equipment controls.]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Your responsibilities







                         You also have responsibilities as employees as indicated on the health and safety law

                         poster in the third column ‘What you must do’.


































































                         The poster is displayed on the notice board]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Your responsibilities







                     What are they?








                     • Follow the training you have received when using any work items


                           your employer has given you.



                     • Take reasonable care of your own and other people’s health and


                           safety.



                     • Co-operate with your employer on health and safety.



                     • Tell someone (your employer, supervisor, or health and safety



                           representative) if you think the work or inadequate precautions are


                           putting anyone’s health and safety at serious risk.



                     • Not intentionally or recklessly  interfere with anything provided in


                           the interests of health, safety and welfare.


















                     Responsibilities are stated the Health and Safety at Work etc. Act 1974 regulation 7,


                     General duties of employees at work.]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Site visitors and the public





                          The following representatives could at various times be encountered on


                          site:


                          •      Clients


                          •      Company Health, Safety and Environmental Managers


                          •      Health & Safety Executive officers (HSE)


                          •      Environment Agency Officers

                          •      Local Authority Environmental Health Officers






                          Please ensure that:


                          •      You are courteous to any visitor seen on site.


                          •      If you are asked a question, you are positive in your response and not


                                 evasive. If you do not know the answer to a question, be honest and


                                 ask them if they need you to find out the answer.


                          •      If you see any visitor in potential danger, please escort them out of


                                 the situation.


                          •      If you see any visitor unsure of what to do or where to go, ask politely

                                 if you can be of assistance.


                          •      If you are asked any questions by a member of the public, direct them


                                 to the site project manager as it could be a member of the Press or


                                 TV. Do not give them answers which could affect John F Hunt or the


                                 Client.]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Before you start work








             Before you start work you should have;





             • Understood this induction





             • Have a method statement for the work package you are undertaking and any


                 individual task sheets for each work activity and ensure you understand it.





             • Have a Risk Assessment for tasks being carried out by you and know the contents

                 and requirements of the document and ensure you understand it.






             • Been given a risk assessment and method statement briefing and a daily activity

                 briefing and you are fully aware of what to do, how to do it safely and the risks


                 involved. PLEASE ensure you understand it.





             All employees  have the right to refuse to work on the grounds of


             health and safety





             If in doubt, please ask.





                                                WE ARE ALL RESPONSIBLE FOR HEALTH,SAFETY & WELLBEING]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Site operating hours















                       • Site operating hours are:







                                •      07:00 – 19:00 Monday to Friday.

                                •      08:00 – 13:00 Saturdays with authorisation.


                                •      No working on Sundays or Bank Holidays without prior consent.






                       •       All persons must sign in/out at the site reception.



                       •       Only enter/exit through the main gate at the gatehouse.






                       •       Do not sign any other person in or out]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Minimum PPE requirements on site













                             The following 6 Point PPE must be worn


                             on site at all times:





                             1. Safety boots with steel toecaps and mid-


                                  sole.

                             2. High vis vest/jacket.


                             3. High Visibility trousers

                             4. Safety helmet


                             5. Hand protection (Gloves)


                             6. Protective eyewear





                             Task specific PPE may also be required:





                             1. Safety Goggles/Glasses  suitable for the


                                  task to be undertaken.

                             2. Dust/face mask suitable for the task to be


                                  undertaken.

                             3. Hearing Protectionsuitable  for the task to


                                  be undertaken.


                             4. Harness/lanyard]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Task specific PPE and RPE]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Site Rules







               Site Rules






               •      Only do works covered in your RA/MS


               •      Wear the right PPE for the task



               •      Consider other workers safety






               Site rules have been made to ensure the health and safety of you and


               your colleagues on this site. They apply to everybody!





               Failure to follow site rules will lead to disciplinary  action being taken


               against you and possible removal  from site





               Serious violations will not be tolerated and will result in immediate


               removal from site






               If you don’t feel safe with the task requested of you don’t do it. Speak



               to your supervisor.]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Safety Culture “Say what you see”



































                                               Task                                                             Description




                                                          Before you start do you have everything you need, e.g. the right permits, PPE, RPE, Training, Tools
                                 1            STOP
                                                          etc.





                                                          Safety Hazards, Look around and see what hazards are associated with the activity that have not
                                 2            THINK       been identified including any present within the immediate and surrounding work area and those
                                                          generated by the activity.





                                                          Implement control measures to remove the hazard or to reduce the risk to as low as reasonable
                                 3             ACT
                                                          practicable.






                                                          Continually review as work progresses and at the end of the Job / task, what have I learnt; did I
                                 4           REVIEW
                                                          create any additional hazards by the work carried out.



                          If the answer is Yes to Part 4 then inform your Contract Manager / Supervisor]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Safety Culture “Say what you see”





        See it
                                                                                                                         Hazard Spotter Cards



        Is there something that

        could cause harm? have


        you just missed being

        harmed? Is there


        something to improve

        upon?




        Sort it



        If so can you do


        something to prevent

        harm without harm to


        yourself? If yes then do it!



        Report it




        Now you’ve done

        something to stop others                                                      What? When?                                                What do you


        being harmed or seen                                                          Where? How?                                                think should be

        something to improve tell


        John F Hunt about it.                                                                                                                    done to make
                                                                                                                                                 things better?

              Complete a Hazard


                      Spotter card.]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[Safety Culture













                  ‘Don’t Walk By’



                  The concept of ‘Don’t Walk By‘ defines the behaviour that anything that is

                  unsafe can be challenged and put right. John F Hunt Regeneration adopts this


                  philosophy and expects  this concept to be taken on board by all led by top


                  management. Let Site Managers and Supervisors know and ensure it is dealt

                  with in good time.



                  Examples can include:


                  •       Unsafe working e.g. working at height, behind barriers; lack of PPE;



                  •       Unsafe conditions e.g. open excavations  without edge protection; faulty

                          plant & equipment; unsecured ladders; dust and noise; dangerous plant


                          movements.


















                                             Don’t walk by. . . make it safe]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Considerate Constructors Scheme








          Voluntary Code of Practice driven by the industry:



                    •        Minimise disturbance to the local neighbourhood.


                    •        Eradicate offensive behaviour and language.



                    •        Raise standards of site management, safety and


                             environmental awareness beyond statutory duties.







          Key Principles:



                    • Considerate and Good Neighbours



                    • Clean & Tidy


                    • Respectful



                    • Safe



                    • Environmentally conscious



                    • Responsible and Accountable]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Drugs and Alcohol



























                 •      It is against site rules to bring or consume drugs/alcohol on site. Any


                        person found in possession or under the influence of drugs or alcohol on


                        site will be removed from site immediately and will not be permitted to



                        return



                 •      John F Hunt operate a random drug and alcohol testing policy. Be aware


                        that you may be selected for random drug and alcohol testing as part of


                        regular site requirements and visits by our testing company. If you refuse



                        to be tested, this will be treated as a positive result and you will be


                        removed from site employment. You are responsible for ensuring that


                        you come to work alcohol and drug free.



                 •      Check with your doctor or pharmacist that medicines that you take will



                        not impair performance e.g. by causing drowsiness. If you are unsure,


                        tell your supervisor]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Mobile Phones







                    •       Mobile phones and tablets are not to be used on site unless


                            authorized






                    •       Authorized persons are:






                              – Managers







                              – Supervisors






                              – Site Emergency calls only











                    • At no time should a mobile phone be used when operating any

                           plant, equipment or tools – if you do you will face disciplinary


                           procedures


                    • Mobile phone zones will be set up on site where phones can

                           be used.]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Smoking on site







                     •      Smoking or Vaping is PROHIBITED, except in specified locations








                     •      Smoking within welfare and management facilities  and working



                            areas is prohibited








                     • Anyone found smoking within controlled areas will be immediately


                            removed from site








                     •      Please place cigarette butts in the ash tray / sand box provided]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Fire and Emergency procedures








               •       Ensure you understand the site Emergency Procedures these are displayed around site.



               •       Constant alarm, fire alarm, make your way to the nearest muster point.




               •       On hearing the fire alarm, which is a continuous blast on an air horn/ electronic siren, follow these
                       procedures:
                          •     Stop work


                          •     Turn off all plant


                          •     Make your job/area safe


                          •     Evacuate to the muster point in an orderly fashion and no running do not use mobile phones.

                          •     Where asbestos works are being carried out asbestos operatives must make their way to their

                                designated muster point within the asbestos work area.

                          •     All persons to go to their local muster point as detailed within the emergency plan.


                          •     Wait for the Fire Marshal to do a roll call and make sure everybody is accounted for

                          •     Do not re-enter the site until the Site Manager has given the all clear


                          •     Do not leave site during an emergency, as you could be reported missing to the Emergency
                                Services]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Raising the alarm
















                      • In the event of an emergency Dial 999 / 112 from any landline



                              or mobile






                      • If the issue is not life threatening assess the situation and


                              advise that IP should be taken to hospital for check over.







                      • Follow the METHANE approach in the event of incident:






                                                     • M – Major Incident Declared


                                                     • E – Exact Location



                                                     • T – Type of Incident


                                                     • H – Hazards present or suspected


                                                     • A – Access routes that are safe


                                                     • N – Number, Type & severity of any casualties


                                                     • E – Emergency services required]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Fire and emergency assembly point










                  • The site Emergency Muster Points are located at areas below:


























                                                      Self
                                                      contained
                                                      unit









                                                                                                                             Main Site
                                                                                                                             welfare
                                                                                                                             offices

                                                                                                                                 Sleeper units
                                                                                                                                                                            Self
                                                                                                                                                                            contained
                                                                                                                                                                            unit
















                                                                                                                     .]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[Fire safety










                    •      Be aware of the risks of fire starting around you





                    •      Place waste in the correct skip





                    •      Don’t dry clothes close to heaters




                    •      Obey ‘No Smoking’ signs





                    •      Know the emergency arrangements




                    •      On this site the fire alarm is raised by sounding the air horn or


                           siren




                    •      If you call the Security control room (SCR) immediately inform the

                           site manager]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[Fire safety


























                      Fire safety



















                    Fire extinguishers can be found



                               in offices and at specific


                        locations around site. Please



                                familiarise yourself with



                                   locations and the fire



                       emergency plan displayed on



                                                            site]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[Reporting accidents, incidents and near misses


















             •      Call for a First Aider immediately  following an injury or if you feel


                    unwell







             •      All accidents no matter how minor, must be reported and recorded in


                    the accident book by the First Aiders.








             •      The accident book is kept in the Site Office









             •      It is also critical  you report any near misses, activities or conditions


                    which could cause an accident








             •      Please report environmental incidents immediately]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[First Aid and Emergency








                   •       Your trained first aiders are:


                   •       John Hawthorn – Site


                   •       Dean Holland –Site/Office



                   •       Hannah Corran - Site/Office


                   •       Usama Babar – Office



                   •       Michael Watts – Office







                   •       First aid kits are kept at:



                   •       Site Office


                   •       Satellite site Welfare/offices



                   •       The nearest hospital is:



                             The County Hospital,




                             Weston Road,



                             Stafford,




                             ST16 3SA



                             TEL: 01785257731



                             A&E is open between 8am – 10pm everyday.]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[Welfare Facilities







          The site welfare facilities  are located at the main Compound.








          Please ensure that you:



          •       Leave them as you would expect to find them – clean and tidy and in


                  full working order




          •       Do not smoke in any of the facilities



          •       Wash your hands thoroughly before eating, drinking and smoking


                  particularly after using the toilet



          •       Do not leave clothes strewn around the changing room floor. Hang


                  everything up or store in lockers



          •       Do not store tools, equipment etc. in the welfare facilities  – they must


                  have their own storage area



          •       Clear all rubbish from the tables and use the bins provided



          •       Do not put wet clothes on the heaters, this is a fire hazard



          •       Keep doors to facilities closed.]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[Welfare Facilities]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[Slips, trips and falls










                   •      Slips, trips and falls are a major cause of accidents








                   •      Keep your workplace tidy, clear as you go.








                   •      Store materials  in the correct manner








                   •      Think about pedestrian walkways and plant



                           routes








                   •      A tidy site helps to create a safe site]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[Manual handling









                  Manual handling is one of the most common causes of injury in the workplace.






                  You must be trained in the correct methods of lifting by your employers and

                  evidence provided  to site management.






                  Use the acronym TILE when assessing loads.


                  T = Task – What does the task require and what is involved in the process

                  of  lifting, carrying, manoeuvring, pushing or pulling a load.



                  I = Individual – The physical capabilities of a person.


                  L = Load – Assess the load in relation to its weight, size, shape, flexibility

                  and rigidity



                  E = Environment – What is the condition of the area where the work is to

                  be undertaken. Inspect the area around the object to be moved and the


                  route to be taken for any obstructions or hazards and the area where the

                  load is to be placed.]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[Environmental protection







           Spillage Response


           Initially contain any spill to ensure that it cannot enter a drain, river or other


           watercourse. Any spillages of hazardous substances must be reported to the site


           management. The spill response team shall then deal with the spill.

           Details of the spill response team can be found on display on the notice board






           What is a spill?


           Accidental discharge into the natural environment (e.g. soil, water) from or out of a;


           • Structure – pipework or tanks within a new or existing structure


           • Vehicle – Burst pipe, leaking engine/hose


           • Container – diesel bowser, oil drum, burst pipe etc.


           • Concrete Wash Out – escape or leak from containment system






           5 steps for dealing with a spill


           S – Stop work, get a spill kit


           P – Protect area around the spill, Prevent the spill from spreading


           I – Inform the correct people about the spill


           L – Limit the impacts of the spill


           L – Log & Learn from the Incident]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[Environmental protection








             When Refuelling


             •       Refuel only at designated area


             •       Use a drip tray, use a funnel or nozzled pump


             •       Ensure Spill Kits are available in the re-fuelling area


             •       In the event of a spill clean up using a spill kit and REPORT it immediately






             Waste management



             •       Ensure waste is segregated  as per the Waste Management Forecast


             •       Keep drums in bunds/drip trays






             Noise and dust


             •       Keep noise on site to a minimum



             •       Turn off plant and equipment when not in use AND REMOVE THE KEYS


             •       Make sure there is a vibration sticker stating what the noise level for that

                     plant/equipment is


             •       If you see airborne dusts, inform the site manager immediately.  There must be


                     no visible dusts on or leaving site]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[Plant Movements















































             •       All persons operating plant must have working Orange and Green flashing beacons
                     and all mirrors in place

             •       Plant operators must wear the seat belts provided.

             •       Plant drivers must keep to designated and plant movement routes, as agreed each
                     morning in the daily safety briefing

             •       Tip points must be agreed, edge bunds in place and skips lowered before travelling.

             •       All dump trucks must have dipped headlights on at all times
             •       2 separate Speed Limits on site - 09mph & 19mph

             •       Pedestrians beware of moving vehicles, always wear high visibility clothing

             •       Pedestrians to keep to pedestrian routes and should be aware of the locations of haul
                     routes and activities each day.

             •       When approaching plant on foot, do not approach until the operator has acknowledged
                     your presence, placed bucket on the ground and isolated the machine.

             •       Mobile phones must not be used whilst operating plant.]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[Traffic and pedestrians









                   •       Site speed limits are 19mph on Rd 2 and 9mph in all other areas





                   •       Hazard lights or flashing beacons must be on when transiting across site






                   •       All vehicles must be reverse parked





                   •       Everyone must keep to all designated routes only






                   •       Do not enter or walk through or along plant movement routes





                   •       Visitors must be accompanied by site supervisors when walking around the


                           works. Access to site will only be permitted with required measures being


                           put in place.]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[Plant safety







                  •       Only competent trained personnel can operate plant demonstrated by either CITB

                          CPCS or NPORS accredited training certificates



                  •       Only plant and equipment that is in date for test & inspection is to be used



                  •       Only use plant and equipment that you have been trained to use


                  •       Ensure a daily pre-use check is completed on the item of plant you use




                  •       Use of mobile phones is not allowed whilst operating plant



                  •       Remove keys when leaving plant




                  •       Observe traffic routes



                  •       Be aware of slewing areas and always stand on the cab side in view of the driver.


                          Always get the drivers attention before approaching the plant]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[Plant safety



























                                                                                                   Zone 1 – Always signal the



                                                                                                   plant operator and receive a



                                                                                                   positive response before


                                                                                                   entering zone 1
















                                                                                                   Zone 2 – Keep out of Zone 2



                                                                                                   at all times during operation]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[Deep excavations









                         Do not enter any excavation unless:


                         • You have a specific method statement and risk assessments relating to the


                              work
             Site specific hazards
                         • You have a permit to enter excavation


                         • You have had a specific site safety induction detailing the risks involved  in

                              excavation  work


                         • The atmosphere within the excavation  has been gas tested and if there is any


                              concern identified the atmosphere must be tested prior to entry

                         • You ensure the excavation  has two safe access points


                         • All excavation and sides are fully protected by installed shoring, trench boxes


                              etc.

                         • All excavations have installed fixed upright edge protection complying with


                              distances set by Work at Height Regulations at a distance of 2 meters from

                              any open edge:


                                             • Top handrail height: 950mm


                                             • No gap bigger than: 470mm

                                             • Toe board height: 150mm


                         • No vehicles or plant shall be within 2 metres of excavation  edge.

                         • Stop blocks to be installed to edges of excavations.]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[Falls from height







                       •      Falls from height contribute to the biggest amount of accidents within the


                              construction industries. Any risk of injury from a fall from any height liable


                              to cause an injury must be controlled , with the height relating to any
             Site specific hazards
                              distance above or below ground






                       •      All falls from height must be controlled by installed upright and fixed edge


                              protection, as shown, installed at the edge of a fall risk





                       •      ‘A’ frames can only be used as a means of prevention to the fall risk, they


                              must be installed a minimum of 2 meters from an open edge, be fixed in


                              position so they cannot be moved and meet the same requirements as


                              the fixed edge protection requirements]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[Potential for soils asbestos contamination







                                                                                                 Asbestos has been buried in the past


                                                                                                 and will be unearthed during


                                                                                                 excavation works.
             Site specific hazards
                                                                                                 All excavation works will be completed



                                                                                                 within the licenced area under the


                                                                                                 watch brief of trained asbestos


                                                                                                 personnel.


                                                                                                 All personnel in the licenced area will



                                                                                                 be trained to work in there and will


                                                                                                 follow the plan of works.]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[Contaminated soils




                  The site is contaminated with harmful chemicals,

                  hydrocarbons, heavy metals, associated with PFA
                  and arsenic associated with chimneys during

                  production.



             Site specific hazards
                  Concentrations vary, but we must assume they are

                  high everywhere.



                  Hot spots have been identified across the site.

                  You must separate yourselves from the
                  contaminated soil by wearing protective  clothing,

                  always.







                  How could you get hurt:





                            •      By eating (ingesting) contaminated material


                            •      By breathing (inhaling) harmful dust or fumes

                            •      By getting some of the chemicals on your skin or in cuts or scratches





                  •      You must wash before eating and at the end of each work period





                  •      You must not smoke because the process of smoking may lead to ingestion

                         of contaminated soil





                  •      You must not eat on site, because of the risk of ingesting contaminated soil.

                         Eat only in the canteen]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[Contaminated soils






                     •      If you get any tar-like substances on your skin, wash them off with a


                            proprietary cleaner, followed by soap and water, and change your clothes





             Site specific hazards
                     •      If you have even the slightest cut or scratch, get it thoroughly cleaned by the

                            First Aider and covered with a waterproof dressing






                     •      You must enter the working area through the DCU and wear the protective

                            coverall provided for the works in the licenced area. These are to be


                            disposed of on exiting the licenced area as per the training provided.]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[Contaminated soils






                     •      You must report any health disorder to the First Aider or the site Safety


                            Officer - headaches, stomach aches, etc.





             Site specific hazards
                     •      You must not go into any trench, pit or other confined space unless you or

                            your supervisor has a permit to work current for the work being done






                     Report to your supervisor if:



                     •      You see any patches of thick black material, blue powders or yellow


                            powders - Keep clear





                     •      You smell anything, especially rotten eggs - Keep clear






                     •      You see any sign of fire - Keep clear






                     •      You find any old containers - Keep clear]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[MAIN SITE HAZARDS





                   Asbestos


                   Hydrocarbons


                   Pulverised Fuel Ash

                   Fall from height
            Site specific hazards

                   Plant movements on site






                  • Control measures detailed in the Method


                       statement and Risk Assessment]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[Permits to work











              •      You must not start work unless


                     you have a valid permit to work


                     for the following activities:






                            Working at height


                            Excavations



                            Confined space entry


                            Hot works


                            Lifting operations


                            Demolition



                            Working near windows and glazing





              •      Make sure you





                        – read and understand the permit


                        – your workforce have been briefed


                        – you have signed onto the permit


                        – keep your permit & a copy of the RAMS with you at all times]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[Housekeeping and Materials Storage









                                •      Site compound to be kept tidy at ALL times





                                •      NO material to be stored in the welfare areas including

                                       offices.





                                •      All tools and equipment must be put in the site stores

                                       when not in use





                                •      Materials stored in compound to be on wooden pallets

                                       and banded together when possible




                                •      All COSHH items to be stored in COSHH stores





                                •      Fuel cans to be labelled and stored in re-fuelling area





                                •      All plant to be locked when not in use and equipment to

                                       be stored securely





                                •      All empty spray paint and grease cartridges must be


                                       disposed of appropriately]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[Hot Works










                All hot works on site shall be:





                •      Undertaken by competent trained personnel


                       only






                •      Undertaken in accordance with specific risk

                       assessments and method statements






                •      Managed by the issue of a hot works permit


                       issued on a daily basis





                •      Managed by a Fire Marshal who will oversee


                       the hot works and continually check adjacent


                       areas for fire risk from sparks





                •      A fire inspection shall be conducted 1 hour


                       after completion of works prior to permit


                       closure.]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[Lifting Operations













                •       Only trained persons to be involved  with lifting operations on site.



                •       Lifting operations to follow a lifting plan.



                •       Lifting plant, including some excavators, must have an in date


                        annual LOLER certificate of thorough examination certificate.



                •       Chains and shackles must be checked before use and must have


                        an in date six monthly LOLER certificate of thorough examination



                        certificate.


                • A permit to lift to be issued before any lifting commences.



                • If you are not a trained slinger/signaller you are not competent or


                        authorised to sling loads or give signals to machine operators on


                        this site.]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[Lifting operations with an excavator











                 •       Only competent trained personnel can operate it








                 •       Be aware of slewing areas







                 •       Do not climb on any section of the machine unless authorised to


                         do so








                 •       Do not walk under any suspended load








                 •       All lifts must be undertaken with



                         a banksman in attendance








                 •       Exclusions zones to be in place.]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[Confined spaces






                    •     All confined spaces atmospheres must be gas tested prior to any entry




                    •     All persons must be trained to enter a Confined Space and have the correct


                          equipment with certification




                    •     A Confined Space Entry permit is required before any work starts which is only valid

                          for the stated period, 24 hrs, then must be cancelled




                    •     Any excavations deeper than 1.2m and above require a permit if only one point of

                          access/egress available




                    •     A top man must be present at all times





                    •     Do not take gas cylinders into a confined space]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[Signs on site












                                                               Red Prohibitive (Must not do)


                                                                     No Smoking, No unauthorised entry, Do not touch,

                                                                     No vehicles, etc.










                                                               Blue Mandatory (Must do)

                                                                     Wear hard hat, Wear Hand protection,

                                                                     Wear hearing protection, Sound horn, etc.











                                                               Yellow Caution (Hazard warning)

                                                                     Fragile roof, High voltage, Asbestos, Fork lift trucks,


                                                                      low headroom, etc.









                                                               Green Safe Condition (The Safe Way)


                                                                     First aid, Escape route, Assembly Point,

                                                                     Eye wash, Emergency phone, etc.]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[Possible Occupational Diseases on site







               LEPTOSPIROSIS (Weil’s disease)





                                                                What is Leptospirosis? This is a serious and sometimes fatal infection that is
                                                                transmitted to humans by contact with urine from infected rats. The Hardjo form of

                                                                leptospirosis - This is transmitted from cattle to humans.

                                                                What are the symptoms? Both disease start with a flu-like illness with a persistent

                                                                and severe headache.
                                                                Who is at Risk? Anyone who is exposed to rats, rat or cattle urine or to fetal fluids

                                                                from cattle is at risk.





                PSITTACOSIS


                                                                What is Psittacosis? This is a rare infectious disease that affects birds including

                                                                pigeons. Salmonella - This may also be present in some bird droppings. It is a
                                                                bacterial infection that can cause significant diarrhoea.

                                                                What are the symptoms? Symptoms are commonly a flu-like illness and

                                                                pneumonia usually appearing 5-19 days after exposure
                                                                Who is at Risk? The risk is mainly during refurbishment, building maintenance or

                                                                demolition work. It is highest where there has been significant contamination.



           How might I catch it? Through cuts and scratches and through the lining of the mouth, throat and eyes after contact

           with infected urine or contaminated water.

           How can I prevent it? Get rid of rats and pigeons. Do not touch them with unprotected hands. Cover all broken skin
           with waterproof plasters. Wash your hands before eating, drinking or smoking.

           What else should I do? Report any illness to your doctor. Make sure you tell the doctor that you work on a site.

           These disease are much less severe if treated promptly.]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[Thank you for listening




































                                    Do you have any questions?]]></page></pages></Search>