<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="67"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Phoenix 10 - Walsall]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Site Health, Safety & Environmental induction]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[General Information








                    •      This site health, safety and environmental induction will tell you about the project

                           and the arrangements that have been made to control the health, safety and

                           environmental risks during the works.




                    •      These Health, Safety, Environmental (HSE) and security rules stipulate the

                           minimum requirements for the safe completion of this project.



                    •      Health and safety is everyone’s responsibility. If you observe an unsafe


                           act/situation or receive an injury whilst at work, YOU MUST REPORT IT!



                    •      Question unsafe acts and be open to change when questioned without

                           confrontation.




                    •      Please present CSCS and/or CPCS cards and all other certification to the site

                           manager if you are operating plant, equipment and tools on site for the work you

                           are employed to undertake. No cards = no work on site.




                    •      Please make sure you have understood this induction and the rules on this

                           project. If in doubt, ask. Never assume.



                    •      Please ensure you have signed onto the appropriate Risk Assessment/Method


                           statement (RAMS) before commencing work. If it is not detailed in the RAMS

                           then do not do it and consult your supervisor.



                    •      Do not wear PPE when using local shops.]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[General Information








                    John F Hunt Regeneration Ltd are certificated to:






                    •      ISO9001:2015 – Quality Management. This is the international standard that

                           specifies requirements for a quality management system (QMS). Organizations

                           use the standard to demonstrate the ability to consistently provide products and


                           services that meet customer and regulatory requirements;






                    •      ISO14001:2015 – Environmental Management System. The international

                           standard that specifies the requirements for an environmental management

                           system that an organization can use to enhance its environmental performance;






                    •      ISO45001:2018 – Occupational Health and Safety Management System.

                           This is a new international standard that provides a framework for an


                           organization to manage risks and opportunities to help prevent work-related

                           injury and ill health to workers.






                    Employees and contractors have a responsibility to work in accordance with these

                    standards and strive for continual improvement.]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Project details






                  Client:                     Henry Boot Developments



                  Site Manager: Laurence Kennel




                  Operations Manager: Julian Geer




                  The works consist of the following commencing in March 2022 –






                                   • Installation of temporary and permanent site welfare for project.



                                  • Setup Water treatment plant and quarantine area


                                  • Environmental and ground water monitoring


                                  • Demolition of existing building on site.


                                  • Drill and grouting works to identified shafts across the site and install shaft caps.


                                  • Drill and grout of mine stabilisation works


                                  • Setup of processing area in James Bridge area of site.


                                  • Service relocation of 11kv electric cable.


                                  • Earthworks commencement of the Alumwell site.


                                  • Concrete break out and demolition works site wide.


                                  • IMI earthworks, landscaping and reprofiling.


                                  • Works to canal along northern boundary with site, and the southern boundary of the canal within Zone 5,

                                       to enable excavation works to be completed.]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Project details - disciplines of works on site.







                             • Installation of new utilities, deep drainage, comms, power, water, gas.



                             • Construction of attenuation pond, and associated retaining walls / engineered slopes and structures and
                                  connections to exiting surface water system.


                             • Asbestos management.


                             • Permanent roading network installation/drainage and comms. Permanent access road installation to

                                  telecom communications.


                             • Management of works around the boundary in proximity to boundary walls.]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Project details






             • Site Overview Plan.]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Project details






             • Site Layout Plan.










                                                                                                                                                        IMI Site




                                                                                                                                                        Alumwell Site






                                                                                                                                                         James Bridge

                                                                                                                                                         site




                                                                                                                                                        Underpass to


                                                                                                                                                        IMI site



                                                                                                                                                         Bridge to zone


                                                                                                                                                         5



                                                                                                                                                         Site Entrance

                                          Zone 5

                                                                                                                                                         Site Welfare





                                                                                                                                                         Buildings to be


                                                                                                                                                         demolished]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Key Personnel on Site










            Snr. Project Manager:                                                                 Julian Geer







            Project Director:                                                                     Ashley Tolley






            Site Manager:                                                                         Laurence Kennel






            Sub Agent:                                      Gary Hutton







            General Foreman:                           Thomas Hill






            Foreman:                                                                               John Armstrong







            Health, Safety & Environmental:  Steve Blundell]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Site operating hours













                       •      Site operating hours are:





                                •      07:00 – 19:00 Monday to Friday

                                •      08:00 – 13:00 Saturdays with authorization


                                •      No working on Sundays or Bank Holidays without prior consent




                       •       All persons must sign in/out at the site security and sign on to the daily briefing



                       •       Only enter/exit through the main gate house



                       •       All personnel will, as deemed necessary, have their temperature taken at the gate, prior to

                               entry being permitted. Temperatures over 37.5°C will result in being retested again after 10

                               minutes. Should the second test not be in the required parameters then access will be

                               denied to site and advised to go and get a covid test.



                       •       Do not sign any other person in or out



                       •       Due to residential neighboring properties, noise restrictions mean that no heavy plant or

                               noise excessive tasks can commence before 07:30am and must end by 19:00pm.]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Coronavirus (Covid-19)




















         Coronavirus is a virus that affects the respiratory system (lungs). Covid-19 is the

         Infection and can be spread between people within 2 metres of each other, possibly

         inhaled into the lungs via air born water droplets from a cough or a sneeze.


         Infection can be transferred by hand to face after touching an infected surface or

         object.


         Site management to use the CITB toolbox on Coronavirus talk to communicate


         common controls.



          Wherever possible travel to site alone, using your own transport (for example, a car


                 or bicycle). Avoid public transport.


          Always keep at least 2 meters away from other workers. Work to be planned to


                 prevent close working, if this is not possible then face coverings must be worn.



          Communicate from at least 2m distance.



          Bring your own meals and refillable drinking bottles. Do not share items (for

                 example, cups).]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Coronavirus (Covid-19)




















         Cleaning - Extra cleaning will be carried out on site, particularly in the following areas:






          Taps and washing facilities,





          Toilet flush and seats,





          Door handles and push plates,





          Handrails on staircases and corridors,





          Food preparation, eating surfaces and appliances,






          Telephone equipment, Keyboards, photocopiers and other office equipment.





          Lift and hoist controls, machinery and equipment controls.]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Coronavirus (Covid-19)











                                                                                                   Do not share lockers in changing rooms.

                                                                                                   Briefings will be undertaken outside

                                                                                                          observing the 2 m distancing.

                                                                                                   Follow signage communicating


                                                                                                          coronavirus information such as ‘only one

                                                                                                          person at a time in toilet’

                                                                                                   Keep 2 m distance when entering and


                                                                                                          leaving site.

                                                                                                   Wash your hands when you arrive on site,

                                                                                                          regularly throughout the day (especially if

                                                                                                          you sneeze or cough and after eating or

                                                                                                          handling food) and again when you leave


                                                                                                          site.




                                                                                                  Wash your hands video

                                                                                                  https://youtu.be/bQCP7waTRWU]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Your responsibilities








                        You have responsibilities as employees as indicated on the health and safety law

                        poster in the third column ‘What you must do’.

































































                        The poster is displayed on the notice board]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Your responsibilities








                     What are they?









                     • Follow the training you have received when using any work items


                           your employer has given you.



                     • Take reasonable care of your own and other people’s health and


                           safety.



                     • Co-operate with your employer on health and safety.



                     • Tell someone (your employer, supervisor, or health and safety


                           representative) if you think the work or inadequate precautions are



                           putting anyone’s health and safety at serious risk.



                     • Not intentionally or recklessly interfere with anything provided in


                           the interests of health, safety and welfare.











                     Responsibilities are stated the Health and Safety at Work etc. Act 1974 regulation 7,

                     General duties of employees at work.]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Site visitors and the public









                          The following representatives could at various times be encountered on


                          site:


                          •      Client


                          •      Company Health, Safety and Environmental Managers


                          •      Health & Safety Executive officers (HSE)


                          •      Environment Agency Officers


                          •      Local Authority Environmental Health Officers






                          Please ensure that:

                          •      You are courteous to any visitor seen on site.


                          •      If you are asked a question that you are positive in your response.


                          •      If you see any visitor in potential danger, please escort them out of


                                 the situation.


                          •      If you see any visitor and unsure of what to do or where to go, ask


                                 politely if you can be of assistance.


                          •      If you are asked any questions by a member of the public, direct them


                                 to the site project manager as it could be a member of the Press or


                                 TV. Do not give them answers which could affect John F Hunt or the

                                 Client.]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Before you start work









             Before you start work you should have;





             • Understood this induction






             • Have a method statement for the work package you are undertaking and any

                 individual task sheets for each work activity





             • Have a Risk Assessment for tasks being carried out by you and know the contents


                 and requirements of the document





             • Have been given site daily activity briefing and you are fully aware of what to do,


                 how to do it safely and the risks involved.





             All employees have the right to refuse to work on the grounds of


             health and safety





             If in doubt, please ask.







                                    WE ARE ALL RESPONSIBLE FOR HEALTH & SAFETY - LEGALLY AND MORALLY]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Minimum PPE requirements on site













                             The following 5 Point PPE must be worn

                             on site at all times: Mandatory






                             1. Safety boots with steel toecaps and mid-

                                  sole no rigger boots


                             2. High vis Orange vest/jacket/long sleeves

                                  and pants, ankle to wrist cover.


                             3. Safety helmet


                             4. Safety gloves

                             5. Protective eyewear





                             Check your risk assessment and site


                             requirements. The following PPE may be


                             required: Task Specific





                             1. Safety Goggles

                             2. Dust mask


                             3. Hearing Protection


                             4. Harness/lanyard

                             5. Face Masks – RPE]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Site Rules








               Site Rules






               •       Only do works covered in your RA/MS


               •       Wear the right PPE for the task


               •       Consider other workers safety

               •       Be courteous of our neighbours.










               Site rules have been made to ensure the health and safety of you and your


               colleagues on this site. They apply to everybody!




               Failure to follow site rules will lead to disciplinary action being taken against


               you and possible removal from site




               Serious violations will not be tolerated and will result in immediate removal


               from site






               If you don’t feel safe with the task requested of you STOP and speak to


               your supervisor.]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[CSCS / CPCS










                                                                                           All persons requesting to go on to


                                                                                           site must hold a valid in date CSCS



                                                                                           and CPCS/NPORS or relevant card


                                                                                           for your role.]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[Safety Culture






        See it                                                                                                           Hazard Spotter Cards




        Is there something that

        could cause harm? have


        you just missed being

        harmed? Is there


        something to improve

        upon?



        Sort it




        If so can you do


        something to prevent

        harm without harm to


        yourself? If yes then do it!



        Report it




        Now you’ve done                                                                                                                          What do you

        something to stop others                                                      What? When?

        being harmed or seen                                                          Where? How?                                                think should be


        something to improve tell                                                                                                                done to make


        John F Hunt about it.                                                                                                                    things better?



              Complete a Hazard

                      Spotter card.]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Safety Culture








           STAR Assessment]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Safety Culture












                  ‘Don’t Walk By’


                  The concept of ‘Don’t Walk By‘ defines the behaviour that anything that is


                  unsafe can be challenged and put right. John F Hunt Regeneration adopts this


                  philosophy and expects this concept to be taken on board by all led by top

                  management. Let Site Managers and Supervisors know and ensure it is dealt


                  with in good time.



                  Examples can include:


                  Housekeeping.


                  •       Unsafe working e.g. working at height, behind barriers; lack of PPE;


                  •       Unsafe conditions e.g. open excavations without edge protection; faulty


                          plant & equipment; unsecured ladders; dust and noise; dangerous plant


                          movements.













                                             Don’t walk by. . . make it safe]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Safety Culture










                     Hierarchy Of Controls]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Safety Culture










              Safety Stations                                                                                                                              Safe Zones.










                                                                                                                                                           Sign on


                                                                                                                                                           Stations for



                                                                                                                                                           each work


                                                                                                                                                           Area.








                                                                                                                                                           Spill Kit


                                                                                                                                                           locations.







                                                                                                                                                           First Aid.]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Considerate Constructors Scheme










          Voluntary Code of Practice driven by the industry:



                    •        Minimise disturbance to the local neighbourhood.



                    •        Eradicate offensive behaviour and language.


                    •        Raise standards of site management, safety and


                             environmental awareness beyond statutory duties.






          Key Principles:




                    • Considerate and Good Neighbours



                    • Clean & Tidy



                    • Respectful


                    • Safe



                    • Environmentally conscious



                    • Responsible and Accountable]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Drugs and Alcohol


























                 •      It is against site rules to bring or consume drugs/alcohol on site. Any


                        person found in possession or under the influence of drugs or alcohol on


                        site will be removed from site immediately and will not be permitted to


                        return



                 •      John F Hunt operate a random drug and alcohol testing policy. Be aware



                        that you may be selected for random drug and alcohol testing as part of


                        regular site requirements and visits by our testing company. If you refuse


                        to be tested, this will be treated as a positive result, and you will be



                        removed from site. You are responsible for ensuring that you come to


                        work alcohol and drug free.



                 •      Check with your doctor or pharmacist that medicines that you take will


                        not impair performance e.g. by causing drowsiness. If you are unsure,


                        tell your supervisor]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Mobile Phones







                    •       Mobile phones and tablets are not to be used on site unless















                              – It is a site Emergency


                              – You are stood in a place of safety




























                    • At no time should a mobile phone be used when operating any

                           plant, equipment, tools or a site vehicle or your own vehicle –


                            if you do, you will face disciplinary procedures.


                    • Mobile phone zones will be set up on site to allow you to take


                           calls. These will be clearly demarcated.]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[Smoking on site









                     •      Smoking or Vaping is PROHIBITED, except in specified locations








                     •      Smoking within welfare and management facilities and working


                            areas is prohibited








                     •      Anyone found smoking within controlled areas will be immediately


                            removed from site








                     •      Please place cigarette butts in the ash tray / sand box provided]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[Fire and Emergency procedures






               •       Ensure you understand the site Emergency Procedures these are displayed around site.




               •       If an emergency procedure is to take place, make your way to the site muster point at the compound
                       entrance.



               •       On hearing the fire alarm, which is a continuous blast on an air horn/electronic siren/3 horns on a

                       machine/radio comms emergencyx3, follow these procedures:
                          •     Stop work – where it is safe to do so


                          •     Isolate all plant and perform shut down procedures.


                          •     Evacuate to the muster point in an orderly fashion and no running do not use mobile phones.

                          •     In the Licenced area - All person to make there way to a place of safety next to the

                                decontamination units. All person must go through the DCU in a safe manner. If there is a fire
                                in the decontamination unit person must go to the agreed location of that licenced area.

                          •     Outside the licenced area – all persons to go to the muster point at the compound entrance.


                          •     Wait for the Fire Marshal to do a roll call and make sure everybody is accounted for


                          •     Do not re-enter the site until the Site Manager has given the all clear

                          •     Do not leave site during an emergency, as you could be reported missing to the Emergency

                                Services]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[Raising the alarm















                      •       Inform the site Manager immediately so that security can be informed





                      •       In the event of an emergency Dial 999 / 112 from any landline or mobile





                      •       If the issue is not life threatening assess the situation and advise that IP


                              should be taken to hospital for check over.





                      •       Follow the METHANE approach in the event of incident:





                                                     •      M – Who is making the call


                                                     •      E – Type of Incident

                                                     •      H – Hazards present or suspected


                                                     •      T – Type of hazard occuring


                                                     •      A – Access routes that are safe

                                                     •      N – Number, Type & severity of any casualties


                                                     •      E – Emergency services required]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[Fire and emergency assembly point












                 • The site Emergency Muster Point is located in the back of the


                         carpark of the compound shown.


                 • If the muster point is the point of the emergency – the secondary


                         muster point will be the main entrance.





















































                                                                                                                     .]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[Fire safety









                    •      Be aware of the risks of fire starting around you





                    •      Place waste in the correct skip





                    •      Don’t dry clothes close to heaters





                    •      Obey ‘No Smoking’ signs




                    •      Know the emergency arrangements





                    •      On this site the fire alarm is raised by sounding the air horn or

                           siren





                    •      If you call the Security control room (SCR) immediately inform the

                           site manager]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[Fire safety


























                      Fire safety


















                          Fire extinguishers can be found



                                     in offices and at specific



                              locations around site. Please



                                      familiarise yourself with


                                         locations and the fire



                             emergency plan displayed on



                                                                  site]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[Reporting accidents, incidents and near misses













          •       Call for a First Aider immediately following an injury or if you feel unwell







          •       Follow procedure for accessing the Licenced area in event of emergency.





          •       All accidents no matter how minor, must be reported and recorded in the


                  accident book by the First Aiders on the day of the accident.






          •       The accident book is kept in the Site Office







          •       It is also critical you report any near misses, activities or conditions which


                  could cause an accident






          •       ALL Environmental and Health and Safety incidents are to be reported to


                  the site manager.]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[First Aid and Emergency







                   First Aiders on Site:



                   - Laurence Kennel




                   -       Julian Geer


                   -       Thomas Hill




                   -       John Armstrong



                   •       First aid kits are kept at:



                   •       Site Office



                   •       Satellite site offices



                   •       Site Vehicles








                   •       The nearest hospital is:

                                 Manor Hospital,


                                 Moat Road,

                                 Walsall,


                                 WS2 9PS


                                 Telephone: 01922 721172

                   Route maps to the A&E departments are at reception]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[Hospital Location
























                                                                                                                                                                    Walsall Manor
                                                                                                                                                                    Hospital
                                                                                                                                                                    Moat Rd
                                                                                                                                                                    Walsall
                                                                                                                                                                    WS2 9PS





























                                                                                                                                                                    Phoenix 10, John F
                                                                                                                                                                    Hunt Reservoir
                                                                                                                                                                    Place Walsall WS2
                                                                                                                                                                    9RZ]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[Your First Aiders are





















































                 John Armstrong                                    Laurence Kennel                                Thomas Hill                                 Julian Geer
                 Foreman                                           Site Manager                                   General Foreman                             Operations Manager

                 07929 700 288                                     07816 128 466                                  07977 184 144                               07816 088 598]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[Welfare Facilities










          The site welfare facilities are located at the main Compound.








          Please ensure that you:



          •       Leave them as you would expect to find them – clean and tidy and in


                  full working order



          •       Do not smoke in any of the facilities



          •       Wash your hands thoroughly before eating, drinking and smoking



                  particularly after using the toilet



          •       Do not leave clothes on the floor of the changing room. Hang


                  everything up or store in lockers



          •       Do not store tools, equipment etc. in the welfare facilities – they must


                  have their own storage area



          •       Clear all rubbish from the tables and use the bins provided



          •       Do not put wet clothes on the heaters, this is a fire hazard



          •       Keep doors to facilities closed.]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[Welfare Facilities – main works and fire site plan]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[Welfare Facilities – Main works Layout Temp]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[Slips, trips and falls










                   •      Slips, trips and falls are a major cause of accidents








                   •      Keep your workplace tidy, clear as you go.








                   •      Store materials in the correct manner








                   •      Think about pedestrian walkways and plant



                          routes








                   •      A tidy site helps to create a safe site]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[Manual handling







                  Manual handling is one of the most common causes of injury in the workplace.





                  You must be trained in the correct methods of lifting by your employers and evidence
                  provided to site management.





                  Use the acronym TILE when assessing loads.






                     T = Task – What does the task require and what is involved in the process of

                     lifting, carrying, manoeuvring, pushing or pulling a load.


                     I = Individual – The physical capabilities of a person.


                     L = Load – Assess the load in relation to its weight, size, shape, flexibility and


                     rigidity


                     E = Environment – What is the condition of the area where the work is to be


                     undertaken. Inspect the area around the object to be moved and the route to be

                     taken for any obstructions or hazards and the area where the load is to be

                     placed.]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[Environmental protection







           Spillage Response


           Initially contain any spill to ensure that it cannot enter a drain, river or other

           watercourse. Any spillages of hazardous substances must be reported to the site


           management. The spill response team shall then deal with the spill.


           Details of the spill response team can be found on display on the notice board






           What is a spill?


           Accidental discharge into the natural environment (e.g. soil, water) from or out of a;


           • Structure – pipework or tanks within a new or existing structure


           • Vehicle – Burst pipe, leaking engine/hose

           • Container – diesel bowser, oil drum, burst pipe etc.


           • Concrete Wash Out – escape or leak from containment system






           5 steps for dealing with a spill


           S – Stop work, get a spill kit


           P – Protect area around the spill, Prevent the spill from spreading


           I – Inform the correct people about the spill


           L – Limit the impacts of the spill


           L – Log & Learn from the Incident]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[Environmental protection







             When Refuelling


             •       Refuel at designated areas


             •       Use a drip tray, use a funnel or nozzled pump



             •       Ensure Spill Kits are available in the re-fuelling area


             •       In the event of a spill clean up using a spill kit and REPORT it immediately






             Waste management


             •       Ensure waste is segregated as per the Waste Management Forecast


             •       Keep drums in bunds/drip trays







             Noise and dust


             •       Keep noise on site to a minimum


             •       Turn off plant and equipment when not in use AND REMOVE THE KEYS


             •       Make sure there is a vibration sticker stating what the noise level for that


                     plant/equipment is


             •       If you see airborne dusts, inform the site manager immediately. There must be

                     no visible dusts on or leaving site]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[Site Vehicles











                                                                                •      All drivers driving road vehicles must comply with the

                                                                                       highway code and site rules




                                                                                •      All vehicles must be road worthy and hold a valid MOT




                                                                                •      Any persons driving a site vehicle must have insurance

                                                                                       and hold a valid driving license




                                                                                •      Site vehicles to be kept clean inside and out




                                                                                •      No smoking in site vehicles




                                                                                •      Always be courteous to other road users and give way

                                                                                       to site plant




                                                                                •      When leaving a vehicle unattended turn off the engine

                                                                                       and remove the keys from the ignition




                                                                                •      Adhere to all traffic signs on site and speed limits




                                                                                •      Private vehicles not to be used on site]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[Plant Movements













































             •       All persons operating plant must have working yellow and green flashing beacons and

                     all mirrors in place

             •       Plant operators must wear the seat belts provided.
             •       Plant drivers must keep to designated routes, as agreed each morning in the daily

                     safety briefing
             •       Tip points must be agreed, edge bunds in place and skips lowered before travelling.

             •       Speed limits to be adhered too

             •       Pedestrians beware of moving vehicles, always wear high visibility clothing
             •       Pedestrians to keep to pedestrian routes and should be aware of the locations of haul

                     routes and activities each day.

             •       When approaching plant on foot, do not approach until the operator has acknowledged
                     your presence, place bucket on the ground and isolated the machine.


             •       Mobile phones must not be used whilst operating plant, zero tolerance]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[Traffic and pedestrian routes









                   •      Everyone must know and keep to all designated pedestrian routes only





                   •      Do not enter or walk through or along plant movement routes






                   •      Visitors must be accompanied by site supervisors when walking around the


                          works. Access to site will only be permitted with required measures being


                          put in place.]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[Plant safety





                  •       Only competent trained personnel can operate plant demonstrated by either CITB


                          CPCS or NPORS accredited training certificates



                  •       Only plant and equipment that is in date for test & inspection is to be used



                  •       Only use plant and equipment that you have been trained to use


                  •       Ensure a daily pre-use check is completed on the item of plant you use



                  •       Use of mobile phones is not allowed whilst operating plant




                  •       Remove keys when leaving plant


                  •       All plant to be parked at site compound over night.



                  •       Observe traffic routes




                  •       Be aware of slewing areas and always stand on the cab side in view of the driver.

                          Always get the drivers attention before approaching the plant]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[Plant safety












                                                                                                   Zone 1 – Always signal the


                                                                                                   plant operator and receive a



                                                                                                   positive response. Making



                                                                                                   sure plant is isolated before


                                                                                                   entering zone 1

















                                                                                                   Zone 2 – Keep out of Zone 2


                                                                                                   at all times during operation]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[Deep excavations








                         Do not enter any excavation unless:


                         • You have a specific method statement and risk assessments relating to the

                              work
             Site specific hazards

                         • You have a permit to enter excavation

                         • You have had a specific site safety induction detailing the risks involved in


                              excavation work


                         • The atmosphere within the excavation has been gas tested and if there is any

                              concern identified the atmosphere must be tested prior to entry


                         • You ensure the excavation has two safe access points

                         • All excavation and sides are fully protected by installed shoring, trench boxes


                              etc.


                         • All excavations have installed fixed upright edge protection complying with

                              distances set by Work at Height Regulations at a distance of 2 meters from


                              any open edge:

                                             • Top handrail height: 950mm


                                             • No gap bigger than: 470mm


                                             • Toe board height: 150mm

                         • No vehicles or plant shall be within 2 metres of excavation edge.


                         • Stop blocks to be installed to edges of excavations.]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[Potential for soils asbestos contamination












                                                                                                      Site investigation works completed


             Site specific hazards
                                                                                                      previous has identified asbestos

                                                                                                      contamination, If you identify any


                                                                                                      potential asbestos stop works



                                                                                                      immediately and report it to the site


                                                                                                      manager]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[Contaminated soils






                    The site is contaminated with harmful

                    chemicals, hydrocarbons, heavy metals,

                    associated with the former smelter

                    Works on the site. Concentrations vary,
             Site specific hazards
                    but we must assume they are high every

                    where. Hot spots have been identified

                    across the site.




                    You must separate yourselves from


                    the contaminated soil by wearing
                    protective clothing, always








                    How could you get hurt:




                              •      By eating (ingesting) contaminated material

                              •      By breathing (inhaling) harmful dust or fumes

                              •      By getting some of the chemicals on your skin or in cuts or scratches




                    •      You must wash before eating and at the end of each work period





                    •      You must not smoke because the process of smoking may lead to ingestion of

                           contaminated soil




                    •      You must not eat on site, because of the risk of ingesting contaminated soil.

                           Eat only in the canteen]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[Contaminated soils







                     •      You must report any health disorder to the First Aider or the site Safety


                            Officer - headaches, stomach aches, etc.



             Site specific hazards




                     Report to your supervisor if:




                     •      You see any patches of thick black material, blue powders or yellow

                            powders - Keep clear






                     •      You smell anything, especially rotten eggs - Keep clear





                     •      You see any sign of fire - Keep clear






                     •      You find any old containers - Keep clear]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[Permits to work









              •      You must not start work unless


                     you have a valid permit to work


                     for the following activities:







                            Working at height


                            Excavations


                            Confined space entry


                            Hot works



                            Lifting operations


                            Demolition





              •      Make sure you





                        – read and understand the permit


                        – your workforce have been briefed


                        – you have signed onto the permit



                        – keep your permit & a copy of the RAMS with you at all times]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[Hot Works









                All hot works on site shall be:






                •      Undertaken by competent trained personnel


                       only





                •      Undertaken in accordance with specific risk


                       assessments and method statements






                •      Managed by the issue of a hot works permit

                       issued on a daily basis






                •      Managed by a Fire Marshal who will oversee


                       the hot works and continually check adjacent

                       areas for fire risk from sparks






                •      A fire inspection shall be conducted 1 hour


                       after completion of works prior to permit


                       closure.]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[Housekeeping and Materials Storage








                                •      Site compound to be kept tidy at ALL times





                                •      NO material to be stored in the welfare areas including

                                       offices.




                                •      All tools and equipment must be put in the site stores


                                       when not in use




                                •      Materials stored in compound to be on wooden pallets

                                       and banded together when possible





                                •      All COSHH items to be stored in COSHH stores





                                •      Fuel cans to be labelled and stored in re-fuelling area




                                •      All plant to be locked when not in use and equipment to

                                       be stored securely






                                •      All empty spray paint and grease cartridges must be

                                       disposed of appropriately]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[Signs on site












                                                               Red Prohibitive (Must not do)

                                                                     No Smoking, No unauthorised entry, Do not touch,


                                                                     No vehicles, etc.









                                                               Blue Mandatory (Must do)

                                                                     Wear hard hat, Wear Hand protection,

                                                                     Wear hearing protection, Sound horn, etc.











                                                               Yellow Caution (Hazard warning)


                                                                     Fragile roof, High voltage, Asbestos, Fork lift trucks,

                                                                      low headroom, etc.










                                                               Green Safe Condition (The Safe Way)

                                                                     First aid, Escape route, Assembly Point,


                                                                     Eye wash, Emergency phone, etc.]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[Lifting Operations











                •       Only trained persons to be involved with lifting operations on site.



                •       Lifting operations to follow a lifting plan.




                •       All personnel involved in a lift must be briefed on the lift plan.


                •       Lifting plant, including some excavators, must have an in date



                        annual LOLER certificate of thorough examination certificate.



                •       Chains and shackles must be checked before use and must have


                        an in date six monthly LOLER certificate of thorough examination


                        certificate.


                • A permit to lift to be issued before any lifting commences.



                •       If you are not a trained slinger/signaller you are not competent or



                        authorised to sling loads or give signals to machine operators on


                        this site.



                •       Lifting operations must be supervised by a lift supervisor.]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[Lifting operations with an excavator











                 •       Only competent trained personnel can operate it







                 •       Be aware of slewing areas








                 •       Do not climb on any section of the machine unless authorised to


                         do so








                 •       Do not walk under any suspended load








                 •       All lifts must be undertaken with



                         a banksman in attendance








                 •       Exclusions zones to be in place.]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[Demolition


















             • Demolition works have been carried out on the existing



                    building on Reservoir Place.]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[• Security will be inplace on site 24hrs per day.




                        • All personnel will be required to sign in and out of site.



                        • Due to previous and still ongoing security issues on site



                               dog patrols will be used on site.




                        • Please do not interfere with the security dog or handlers
           Site Security


                               as there is a possibility the dog could turn on you.



                        • If you do see suspicious activity or intruders on site,



                               please do not approach or challenge them, inform the



                               site manager immediately.]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[• A Badger sett is currently in the process of being closed



                               in the Alumwell.




                        • All nesting birds are protected and must not be



                               disturbed. If you notice a birds looking like they are


                               building a nest or an active nest location, please inform



                               the site manager. Do not disturb it, this could lead to
           Ecology      • Prior to felling any trees, shrubs or bushes they must first

                               prosecution.









                               be inspected by an ecologist.]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[Possible Occupational Diseases on site








               LEPTOSPIROSIS (Weil’s disease)




                                                                What is Leptospirosis? This is a serious and sometimes fatal infection that is

                                                                transmitted to humans by contact with urine from infected rats. The Hardjo form of

                                                                leptospirosis - This is transmitted from cattle to humans.
                                                                What are the symptoms? Both disease start with a flu-like illness with a persistent

                                                                and severe headache.

                                                                Who is at Risk? Anyone who is exposed to rats, rat or cattle urine or to fetal fluids
                                                                from cattle is at risk.






                PSITTACOSIS


                                                                What is Psittacosis? This is a rare infectious disease that affects birds including
                                                                pigeons. Salmonella - This may also be present in some bird droppings. It is a

                                                                bacterial infection that can cause significant diarrhoea.

                                                                What are the symptoms? Symptoms are commonly a flu-like illness and
                                                                pneumonia usually appearing 5-19 days after exposure

                                                                Who is at Risk? The risk is mainly during refurbishment, building maintenance or

                                                                demolition work. It is highest where there has been significant contamination.



           How might I catch it? Through cuts and scratches and through the lining of the mouth, throat and eyes after contact

           with infected urine or contaminated water.
           How can I prevent it? Get rid of rats and pigeons. Do not touch them with unprotected hands. Cover all broken skin

           with waterproof plasters. Wash your hands before eating, drinking or smoking.

           What else should I do? Report any illness to your doctor. Make sure you tell the doctor that you work on a site.
           These disease are much less severe if treated promptly.]]></page><page Index="67"><![CDATA[Thank you for listening


































                            Do you have any questions?]]></page></pages></Search>